Guide to the Edward Robb Ellis Papers ca. 1902-1998 MSS 68 MSS 068
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
Edward Robb Ellis Papers
ca. 1902-1998
MSS 068
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
60.0 linear feet (53 boxes)
The bulk of the collection is a continuous diary kept from 1927 up until Edward Robb Ellis' death in 1998. The diary includes handwritten and typed entries as well as photographs and correspondence and consists of bound volumes and loose pages. Also included in the collection are clippings arranged into subject files, book typescripts and audio and visual media.
Provenance
Papers donated by Edward Robb Ellis in 1993.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions. Appointments are necessary to consult archive and manuscript materials.
Biographical Note
Edward Robb Ellis was born in 1911 in Kewanee, Illinois. He began writing his diary in 1927 and continued writing until his death in 1998. Determined to be a reporter, Edward Ellis attended the journalism program at the University of Missouri and in 1934 took his first job as a professional reporter for the New Orleans Associated Press office. In this position he covered the events of the Great Depression and the political career of Huey Long. After two years in New Orleans, he moved to Oklahoma City and became a journalist for the Oklahoma City Times covering New Deal offices and programs. As part of this position he reported on the Oklahoma Federal Symphony Orchestry, which was funded by the Works Progress Administration. Through this assignment Eddie met and fell in love with the principal violinist, Leatha Sparlin. They married in 1939 and moved to Peoria, Illinois where he worked for the Journal-Transcript. The couple then moved to Chicago where Eddie worked for The Daily News. Their daughter Sandra Gail Ellis was born on December 28, 1942.
Shortly after Sandra's birth, Eddie Ellis became aware that a previous diagnosis of a hernia was incorrect. He anticipated being drafted and consequently sought a commission in the navy. He was unable to receive one due to his low weight. As a result, he joined the navy and reported to training on November 7, 1942. Because diary keeping was prohibited in the armed forced he changed the format of the diary from private entries to letters to his wife and daughter. Ellis detested boot camp, upon finishing he was appointed editor of the navy hospital newspaper called The Bedside Examiner. He used his position to publish editorials promoting enlisted people's rights as well as critiques of war. After basic training he was stationed in Okinawa where he continued to publish a newspaper, this time explicitly to improve the sailors' morale. Four months later the war ended and he returned to the United States. His wife requested a divorce, which he granted the following month and returned to work at The Daily News in Chicago.
Ellis did not fit in under the new management at the newspaper in Chicago however, and he soon left for New York to work at the World Telegram. Ellis loved New York City deeply and would remain in the City for the rest of his life. There he met and married Ruth Kraus. They had an exceptionally happy marriage. After 15 years at the World Telegram Ellis quit after a disagreement with a city editor. He used his time unemployed to write several books, often with Ruth's help. He published four A Diary of the Century, Epic of New York, Echoes of Distant Thunder, and A Nation in Torment.
Ruth died suddently of a heart attack in 1965. Eddie Ellis went on to have several extended romances, one with June Morgan and another with Selma Pezaro. Although Eddie was not a strong presence in his daughter's childhood, he and Sandy became close in her adulthood, writing numerous letters and challenging each other intellectually. He also forged mentoring relationships with other diarists, usually as a result of interviews and through the publication of parts of the diary in A Diary of the Century. His reputation as a diarist led Letts of London to create a diary modeled on his recommendations called "The Ellis Diary".
Edward Robb Ellis died in 1998 of emphysema. Throughout his career as a reporter, Eddie Ellis interviewed numerous political and cultural celebrities including Eleanor Roosevelt, Irving Berlin, Grace Kelley and Herbert Hoover. The diary records his impressions of these famous personalities. Ellis was equally fascinated by the experiences and perceptions of ordinary people. He prided himself on his curiosity and eagerness to learn and considered himself what Shakespeare called "a snapper-up of unconsidered trifles." The diary is a collection of those trifles and Eddie Ellis's attempt, as Pete Hamill writes in the introduction to A Diary of the Century "to freeze time" and reflect on himself and humanity.
Scope and Content Note
The collection is comprised of a continuous diary spanning over sixty years. The diary includes written and typed entries as well as personal correspondence, photographs, magnetic audiotape, Super 8 home movies as well as video and audiocassettes. Also included in the diary are book typescripts, subject files and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings covering a wide range of topics. All materials except media are described to the box-level only.
Arrangement
Series I: Diary The diary contains bound volumes of handwritten and typed entries as well as loose entries, newspaper clippings, photographs and correspondence. The diary is arranged chronologically by year with larger documents in four oversize boxes.
Series II: Subject Files Subject files contain newspaper and magazine clippings grouped by Edward Ellis and organized alphabetically with larger items located in five oversize boxes. Two very large items are located in the map case.
Series III: Book Typescripts Series three contains manuscripts for completed and partially completed books including fiction and non-fiction works. Typescripts are arranged alphabetically by title. This series also includes one oversize box.
Series IV: Media This series contains magnetic audiotapes and cassettes of interviews and correspondence as well as mounted color transparencies, videocassettes and 8mm double film. Media is arranged chronologically with undated materials at the end of the sequence. Access copies are not yet available for this material.
Series I: Diary
Series II: Subject Files
Series III: Book Typescripts
Series IV: Media
Oversize - Series I: Diary
Oversize - Series II: Subject Files
Oversize - Series III: Book Typescripts
Ellis, Edward Robb; Ellis, Ruth Kraus; Emelio, Orion; Emelio, Sandra Gail Ellis; Emelio, Shine; Emelio, Victor; Letts of London.; New Orleans Item.; New York World-Telegram.; Oklahoma City Times.; Peoria Journal-Transcript.; Pezaro, Selma Seskin; Sparlin, Leatha; United Press International. Chicago.; University of Missouri.; Wind, Lucy; Audiotapes.; Caricatures.; Chicago (Ill.); Clippings (information artifacts); Color transparencies.; Diaries.; Ellis, Edward Robb |x Diaries.; Journalists |z United States |v Diaries.; Kewanee (Ill.); New York (N.Y.); Okinawa (Japan); Oklahoma City (Okla.); Peoria (Ill.); Photographs.; Portraits.; Typescripts.; United States |x History |y 20th century.; Videocassettes.
- Series I: Diary
  Scope and Contents note
  The diary contains bound volumes of handwritten and typed entries as well as loose entries, newspaper clippings, photographs and correspondence. The diary is arranged chronologically by year with larger documents in four oversize boxes.
  - 1902-1933 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1938 (Box 2)
  - 1938-1946 (Box 3)
  - 1946-1950 (Box 4)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 5)
  - 1954-1956, 19954-1956 (Box 6)
  - 1956-1958 (Box 7)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 9)
  - 1962-1964 (Box 10)
  - 1964-1966 (Box 11)
  - 1966-1969 (Box 12)
  - 1969-1971 (Box 13)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - 1975-1977 (Box 16)
  - 1977-1979 (Box 17)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 19)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 20)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 21)
  - 1984-1986 (Box 22)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 23)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 24)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 25)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 26)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 27)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 28)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 29)
  - 1995 (Box 30)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 31)
  - 1998-Miscellaneous undated (Box 32)
- Series II: Subject Files
  Subject files contain newspaper and magazine clipping grouped by Edward Ellis and organized alphabetically by first letter with larger items located in five oversize boxes. Two very large items are located in the map case.
  - A-B, undated (Box 32)
  - B-I, undated (Box 33)
  - K-W, undated (Box 34)
  - W-Miscellaneous subjects, undated (Box 35)
- Series III: Book Typescripts
  Series three contains manuscripts for completed and partially completed books including fiction and non-fiction works. Typescripts are arranged alphabetically by title. This series also includes one oversize box.
  - Diary of a Reporter and Diary of a Century, undated (Box 35)
  - Diary of a Century, Echoes of a Distant Thunder, The Ellis Diary and Epic of New York, undated (Box 36)
  - Epic of New York, Erika, Harbor of New York, A Nation in Torment, The Old Man Turns On, A Sexual History of the United States, and Steve, undated (Box 37)
  - Steve, Traitor Within, The Watchdogs, and Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated (Box 39)
- Series IV: Media
  This series contains magnetic audiotapes and audiocassettes of interviews and correspondence as well as mounted color transparencies, videocassettes and 8mm double film. This series is arranged chronologically with undated materials at the end of the sequence. Access copies are not yet available for this material.
  - "#1 Mother's visit to N.Y. 1955" 68.0001 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Double 8mm film, Kodachrome, safety color film, 25 feet
  - "Kewanee" Processed December 13, 1956. 68.0002, ca. 1956 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - "[Emerson, Fontaines, Friseman, Steve Seskin] July-August 1958" 68.0003 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm film, Kodachrome color safety film, 25 ft.
  - "[Geo?] Allen Boat Aug. 1958" 68.0004 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm film, Kodachrome color safety film,
  - "Labor Day 1958 Moira and Don Johnston" 38.0005 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm film, Kodachrome color movie film, 25 feet
  - "Iris and Bill Rassieur, Kay and Bob Burton Supt. 1958" 68.0006 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm Kodachrome color movie film, 25 feet
  - "July 1959 Cologne - the Rhine - Joel and Joyce" 68.0007 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm, Kodachrome color safety film, 25 feet
  - "Sunset and Sandy in NY 1959" 68.0008 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Super 8mm film, Kodak
  - "#1 Washington, D.C. July 19-20, 1960" 68.0009 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - "Geo. Allen on Terrace Mary Frishone July 1961 to Danford [Fla] w Lubells" 68.0010 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm daylight Kodachrome, 25 feet
  - "May 1962 San Juan #3" 68.0011 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm artificial light Kodachrome, 25 feet
  - "1962- Selma Maggie- Terrace, Macy Fireworks, Fire on NJ Pier" 68.0012 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Double 8mm Kodachrome film, 25 feet
  - "#1 Aruba May 1962" also labeled "#4 Aruba" on edge. 68.0013 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Double 8mm Daylight Kodachrome, 25 feet
  - "Ellis Isle June, 1962" 68.0014 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    [Super 8mm?] Kocachrome color movie film
  - " July 1963 Jack [unknown] Maggie Thomas South terrace" 68.0015 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Double 8mm color movie film, 25 feet
  - "Sandy Ellis in N.Y. Oct. 1963" 68.0016 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Double 8mm Dynachrome color movie film, reversal type, 25 feet
  - "April '64 Party at Jacks- Eddie, Ruth, Joan" opposite side labeled "Burtons film" 68.0017, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    [Some sort of 8mm] Kodachrome movie film
  - "1964 summer, Sailing vessels, Riverside Park and point" 68.0018 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Double 8mm Dynachrome color movie film for Daylight, 25 feet
  - Empty canister. Kodachrome II double 8mm., ca. 1966 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    none
  - Unprocessed, 68.0019, ca. 1966 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Unprocessed Double 8mm Dynachrome daylight film, 25 feet
  - "Annapurna" 68.0020, ca. 1957 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Double 8mm Kodachrome color safety film, 25 feet
  - "incomplete" 68.0021, ca. 1957 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Unprocessed Double 8mm Kodachrome color safety film for 8mm magazine cameras.
  - "Dan Mahoney May 4, 1961" 68.0022 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Magnetic Audio tape, Scotch brand .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Dan Mahoney May 4, 1961" 68.0023 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Magnetic Audio Tape, Scotch brand .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Olga Paracka and space shoot May 5, 1961" 68.0024 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand, .25 inch, 300 ft.
  - "Jane Fisher May 5, 1961" 68.0025 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand, .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Mrs. Jane Fisher May 5, 1961" 68.0026 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape
  - "Bob Ruark- Hotel Elysee- Wed May 10, 1961" 68.0027 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, High fidelity recording tape, approx. 225 feet
  - "Larry Smits May 15, 1961 Done" 68.0028 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand, .25 inch 300 feet
  - "one side only Larry Smits May 15, 1961 Done" 68.0029 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand .25 inch 300 feet
  - "May 16, 1961 Roy Jones" 68.0030 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand, .25 inch 300 feet, 3.75 speed
  - "May 16, 1961 Jim Farley, Coke record, Sherman Brown" 68.0031 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Camille Street May 22, 1961" 68.0032 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, high fidelity recording tape, approx. 225 feet
  - " Bob Chernoff May 22, 1961" 68.0033 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, high fidelity, approx 225 feet.
  - "Bob Chernoff and Camilee Street May 22 1961" 68.0034 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, high fidelity, approximately 225 feet
  - "Earle B. Greene May 23, 1961" 68.0035 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    magnetic audiotape, high fidelity, approx 225 feet
  - "Earle B. Greene may 23, 1961" 68.0036 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, high fidelity, approx. 225 feet
  - "Lola Leonard May 28, 1961" 68.0037 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Adela St. Johns June 1, 1961" 68.0038 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Adela St. Johns June 1 1961" 68.0039 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Larry Smits June 11, 1961" 68.0040 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    Magnetic audiotape, Dictape, 300 feet, .25 inch
  - "Paul Snell June 12, 1961" 68.0041 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Paul Snell June 12, 1961" 68.0042 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Ned Moss, Hollywood June 12, 1961" 68.0043 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Eddie Hoff Hollywood June 14, 1961" 68.0044 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Emilie Holden Joe Pasternak Hollywood June 14, 1961" 68.0045 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Mike Romanoff June 14, 1961, Message to Ruthie from Sandy, Joe Pasternak, Emilie Holden" 68.0046 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Milburn McCarty, Jack Whitney July 19, 1961" 68.0047 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Magnetic audiotape, Dictape .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Larry Smits July 11, 1961 done- but other side blank" 68.0048 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Margaret Ray July 14, 1961" 68.0049 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Magnetic audiotape, 300 feet
  - "Ed Weimer July 18 1961" 68.0050 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Magnetic audiotape, Dictape, .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Ed Weimer July 18, 1961" 68.0051 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Bob Harron July 21, 1961" 68.0052 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Leo Dolan July 24, 1961" 68.0053 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    Magnetic audiotape, Dictape, .25 inch 300 feet
  - "Leo Dolan July 24, 1961" 68.0054 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Rickenbacker Aug. 2 1961 Audrey Pearce" 68.0055 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Joe Copps - one side only - Aug. 12, 1961" 68.0056 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Joe Copps Aug. 12, 1961" 68.0057 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Joe Copps Aug. 12, 1961" 68.0058 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Audrey Pierce Aug. 13, 1961" 68.0059 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "W. Averell Harrimar Aug. 27, 1961" 68.0060 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Joe Copps Sept 15, 1961" 68.0061 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Joe Copps Sept 16, 1961" 68.0062 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Arthur Godfrey Sept. 26, 1961" 68.0063 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Morton Downey Sept 28, 1961" 68.0064 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Joe E. Lewis and Sherman Bellingsley Sun. Oct 1, 1961" 68.0065 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Mike Wallace Show - PM East Wed., Oct 4, 1961 and Roseanne Bagrion" 68.0066 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - " Nov. 8, 1963 Ron Tomm (just one side used) Ann Loring Nov. 11, 1963-other side" 68.0067 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, unknown tape brand or length
  - "Larry #2 Nov. 11, 1963" 68.0068 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Audrey Peters of Love and LIfe Dec. 16, 1964" 68.0069 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, Ferrodynamics, .25 inch, 600 feet
  - "Bonnie Bedelia November 30, 1964 and Roy Winsor Dec. 1, 1964" 68.0070 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, Ferrodynamics, .25 inch 600 feet
  - "Luis Sanguino Jan 18, 1965" 68.0071 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, Ferrodynamics, unknown length
  - "Luis Sanguino, Jan 18, 1965" 68.0072 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Tunney Dempsey - double speed" 68.0073, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - "Dempsey one side only" 68.0074, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, audiotape brand, 300 feet
  - unlabeled content, sent to J.T. Ellis Jr. in Chicago by E. Ellis in New Yor, 68.0075, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, Scotch brand, unknown length
  - "David Rounds" 68.0076, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, Burgess.25 inch, 150 feet
  - "Sam Pryor, Bernard Giurbel one side done" 68.0077, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    Magnetic audiotape, Super-thin, audiotape brand, 300 feet
  - "Used by Jack Waugh - Edward Ellis World-Telegram" 68.0078, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Margaret Ray, 68.0079, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape, Super-Thin Audiotape brand, 300 feet
  - Bob Harron, 68.0080, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - "1 and 2" 68.0081, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape, Dicatpe, .25 inch, 300 feet
  - "Only bit of one side used" 68.0082, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape, Super-thin Audiotape brand, 300 feet
  - Mike Wallace, 68.0083, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Milburn McCarty and Sam Pryor, 68.0084, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape, unknown brand and length
  - Hal Thurber, Tom Johnston, Joe Dienbart, 68.0085, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Mrs. Gable and Eddie Hoff, Jack Benny, 68.0086, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Dorothy Pearlman and Chas. Ward, 68.0087, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape, Super-thin audiotape brand, 300 feet
  - Joe Copps re: Ford, 68.0088, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Ross Young and Jennie Sweeting, 68.0089, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape,High Fidelity, Approx 225 feet
  - Joe Copps, Sept 16. 68.0090, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape,Scotch brand, .25 inch 300 feet
  - untitled, 68.0091, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape, Ferrodynamics, 600 feet
  - Norburt Wheeler and Mrs. Pearlman, 68.0092, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Mrs. Gale, Hal Thurber, one side only. 68.0093, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Hal Thurber, Done. 68.0094, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Unlabeled, 68.0095, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape,Dictape, 300 feet
  - Sullivan, Mrs. Nichols, Done. 68.0096, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Magnetic audiotape,Super-thin audiotape, 300 feet
  - Jenny Sweeting, 68.0097, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Magnetic audiotape, unknown brand or length
  - David Rounds and Larry Anerbach, 68.0098, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Vyra and Louis, 68.0099, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "June and Eddie, December 22, 1971 Xmas 1971, #1" 68.0100 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Realistic C-60
  - "Dec. 23, 1971 June and Eddie on pot, #2" 68.0101 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - December 31, 1971, 68.0102 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Scotch 120 min.
  - "June Morgan Feb 24, 1974, June and Eddie Feb. 25, 1974" 68.0103 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "Edward Ellis on radio Feb 18, 1975 ([nobel] show)" 68.0104 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Memorex 90
  - "June Morgan and Edward Ellis Wed. Oct 1, 1975" 68.0105 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Norelco C-90
  - "Xmas '75- me" 68.0106, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Tracs 90
  - "June, Marcia, Eddie July 22, 1976" 68.0107 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "Wad'ya know? Hour 1 with Michael Feldman 2/25/89 hr. 2 on side 2..." 68.0108, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, unknown brand, 60 min.
  - "Ellis- BBC- 1991" 68.0109 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, JVC GI-90
  - "Edward Robb ELlis Canadian Broadcasting Corporation Feb. 11, 1991" 68.0110 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, TDK MA90
  - "Ellis BBC 1991" 68.0111 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Unknown brand and length
  - "Ellis BBC 1991" 68.0112 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Maxell XLI-S60
  - WNYC [NYELO] 10-2-95 Edward Robb Ellis, 68.0113, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, Unknown brand, C-60
  - NYELO 10-2-95, Edward Robb Ellis, 68.0114, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    Audiocassette, TDK MA60
  - The Evening Talk Show with Glenn Mitchell Ellis, A Diary of the century, 13 December 1995 KERA 90.1 Dallas, Ft. Worth Denton. 68.0115 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, Unknown brand or length
  - Edward Robb Ellis 7 March 1997, 68.0116 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, TDK D60
  - Afternoon with Mark Heimberger WDWS Champaign Illinois, thank you card included. 68.0117, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, unknown brand or length
  - KPFK Edward Robb Ellis A Diary of the Century with Sylvia Maguite Pepper, 68.0118, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, Maxell UR60
  - The Heywood Hale Broun Show with guests Roberta Feurelicht and Edward Robb Ellis...68.0119, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Eddie Ellis on CBC, 68.0120, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette,TDK D60
  - Mango Theory, 68.0121, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, TDK, unknown length
  - Friday Lives, BBC with Edward Robb Ellis. 68.0122, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, Norelco 200 C-90
  - "Eliz Irwan Locan 60 Colin St. Rochester, NY 14615" 68.0123, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, Radio Shack Concertape 30
  - Untitled, 68.0124, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    Audiocassette, Sony HE60
  - Edward Ellis and World Panel, 68.0125, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
    Audiocassette, Capitol 60
  - Messages to Myself, Margaret Wheeler, Reader: Elaine Claxton, 68.0126, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Friday Lives- BBC Edward Robb Ellis, 68.0127, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
    Audiocassette, Memorex D60
  - Messages to Myself- Eva Marsh, Reader Shelley Tompson. 68.0128, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Messages to Myself- Sally Sedgman, Reader Amanda Redman. 68.0129, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Untitled, 68.0130, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Untitled, 68.0131, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Poems, 68.0132, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
    Audiocassette, Realistic C-30
  - Eddie Ellis on CBS-TV Aug. 22, 1991. 68.0133 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    VHS, Sony ES T120
  - Eddie Ellis 1991 Interviews, 3 copies in 2 folders. 68.0134, 68.0135 (Box 52, Folder 2a)
    VHS, BASF T120
  - Eddie Ellis 1991 Interviews, 68.0136 (Box 52, Folder 2b)
  - Eddie NY November 13, 1995, 68.0137 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    VHS, Maxell HGX Gold T120
  - Eddie Ellis, CBS Morning News August 14, 1995, 68.0138 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    VHS, TDK, unknown length
  - Eddie Ellis, Today Show (NBC) January 24, 1996, CBS This Morning, Good Morning America (ABC) September 4, 1995. 68.0139, 1995-1996 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    VHS, TDK E-HG
  - Edward Robb Ellis NYU November 13, 1996. 68.0140 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    VHS, TDK EHG T120